[
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Australia banned this song by the Kinks in 1970 due to its transgender theme.",
        "correct": "\"Lola\"",
        "answerA": "\"Lola\"",
        "answerB": "\"All Day and All of the Night\"",
        "answerC": "\"Androgynous\"",
        "answerD": "\"Celluloid Heroes\""
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Lena Horne, a New York based jazz and soul singer was blacklisted from performing in the US during the 1950's due to what?",
        "correct": "Having communist affiliations",
        "answerA": "Having communist affiliations",
        "answerB": "Dating a white man",
        "answerC": "Speaking out against",
        "answerD": "Being addicted to pain pills"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Taylor Swift broke her political silence in 2018 and endorsed which Democratic candidate for US Senate in Tennessee?",
        "correct": "Phil Bredesen",
        "answerA": "Phil Bredesen",
        "answerB": "Al Gore",
        "answerC": "Lamar Alexander",
        "answerD": "Bill Lee"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Which punk legend has refused to sign on to an Israeli musician boycott labelling the effort \"left-wing bullshit.\"",
        "correct": "Johnny Lydon (AKA Johnny",
        "answerA": "Johnny Lydon (AKA Johnny",
        "answerB": "Johnny Ramone",
        "answerC": "Stiv Bators",
        "answerD": "Kurt Cobain"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- The E Street Band guitarist Little Steven once declared that he \"wasn't gonna play\" what South African venue due to its apartheid policies in South Africa. ",
        "correct": "Sun City",
        "answerA": "Sun City",
        "answerB": "Thornybush Game Lodge",
        "answerC": "Swadini",
        "answerD": "Mount Amanzi"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- What is the name of the Alabama concert hall that Ray Charles refused to perform at in 1961 due to its policy on racial segregation?",
        "correct": "Bell Auditorium",
        "answerA": "Bell Auditorium",
        "answerB": "Mark C. Smith Concert Hall",
        "answerC": "Alabama Gulf Coast Music Hall",
        "answerD": "Druid City Music Hall"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- The Gang of Four song \"I Love a Man in a Uniform\" was banned by the BBC during what war? ",
        "correct": "Falkland Islands War",
        "answerA": "Falkland Islands War",
        "answerB": "The India Pakistan Conflict",
        "answerC": "The first Iraq war in 1991",
        "answerD": "The Vietnam War"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Joe Pesci and Frank Sinatra threatened violence against this artist for her views on Pope John Paul the II and her refusal to sing the Star Spangled Banner before a show.",
        "correct": "Sinead O'Conner",
        "answerA": "Sinead O'Conner",
        "answerB": "Joan Biaz",
        "answerC": "Yoko Ono",
        "answerD": "Madonna"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- This all black hardcore punk band was banned in from many venues in  their home town of Washington D.C. because of their raucous shows.",
        "correct": "Bad Brains",
        "answerA": "Bad Brains",
        "answerB": "Living Color",
        "answerC": "Fishbone",
        "answerD": "Death"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- The Dead Kennedys were charged with distribution of harmful matter to minors because of a poster that was included in their 1984 Frankenchrist album. Which artist created it?",
        "correct": "HR Giger",
        "answerA": "HR Giger",
        "answerB": "Salvador Dali",
        "answerC": "Keith Hering",
        "answerD": "Peter Max"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Why was Mike Muir of Suicidal Tendencies detained by the U.S. Secret Service in 1984?",
        "correct": "For  singing the line \"I Shot Reagan!\" in a song",
        "answerA": "For  singing the line \"I Shot Reagan!\" in a song",
        "answerB": "He was suspected of being a drug runner for a California gang",
        "answerC": "He failed to pay taxes in 1978 and in 1981",
        "answerD": "He had three felony warrants out for his arrest"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Kayne West was booed on Saturday Night Live in 2018 for his support of what politician?",
        "correct": "Donald Trump",
        "answerA": "Donald Trump",
        "answerB": "Barack Obama",
        "answerC": "Ronald Reagan",
        "answerD": "Sarah Palin"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- This all female, country trio lost much of their fan base after speaking out against George W Bush and the Iraq war at a London concert in 2003.",
        "correct": "The Dixie Chicks",
        "answerA": "The Dixie Chicks",
        "answerB": "SHeDaisy",
        "answerC": "Lady Antebellum",
        "answerD": "The Band Perry"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- When asked by a CNN host whether she supported the Gulf War in 2003 this pop artist said \"Honestly, I think we should just trust our president in every decision that he makes...\"",
        "correct": "Brittany Spears",
        "answerA": "Brittany Spears",
        "answerB": "Paula Abdul",
        "answerC": "Taylor Swift",
        "answerD": "Christina Aguilera"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- This 1975 song by county music star Loretta Lynn was banned by radio stations across the U.S. when it was released.",
        "correct": "\"The Pill\"",
        "answerA": "\"The Pill\"",
        "answerB": "\"Another Man Loved Me Last Night\"",
        "answerC": "\"Not Gonna Take Your Beatin'\"",
        "answerD": "\"Beautiful Unhappy Home\""
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Who was the first rock musician to be arrest while on stage?",
        "correct": "Jim Morrison",
        "answerA": "Jim Morrison",
        "answerB": "Bill Haley",
        "answerC": "Jimi Hendricks",
        "answerD": "Elvis Presley"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Christian fundamentalists organized record burning protests in 1966 after this rock icon claimed that his band was more popular than Jesus.",
        "correct": "John Lennon",
        "answerA": "John Lennon",
        "answerB": "Brian Love",
        "answerC": "Frank Zappa",
        "answerD": "Mick Jagger"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Which anti-fascist song by the Sex Pistols was both banned and a number one \"hit\" on the U.K. record charts in 1977? ",
        "correct": "\"God Save the Queen\"",
        "answerA": "\"God Save the Queen\"",
        "answerB": "\"No One is Innocent\"",
        "answerC": "\"Holiday in the Sun\"",
        "answerD": "\"Bloody Revolutions\""
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- The BBC banned this song in 1968 from the Beatles due to its alleged sexual connotations.",
        "correct": "\"Happiness is a Warm Gun\"",
        "answerA": "\"Happiness is a Warm Gun\"",
        "answerB": "\"I Am the Walrus\"",
        "answerC": "\"Because\"",
        "answerD": "\"Why Don't We Do it in the Road\""
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- In 2012, this artist said, \"I don't talk about politics because it might influence other people. I don't know enough yet in life to be telling people who to vote for.\"",
        "correct": "Taylor Swift",
        "answerA": "Taylor Swift",
        "answerB": "Selena Gomez",
        "answerC": "Demi Lovato",
        "answerD": "Miley Cyrus"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- After several venues cancelled tour dates in 2018, Fat Mike, lead singer of the punk band NOFX, was forced to apologize for mocking the victims of what tragedy?",
        "correct": "The 2017 mass shooting at Harvest Country Music Festival in Las Vegas",
        "answerA": "The 2017 mass shooting at Harvest Country Music Festival in Las Vegas",
        "answerB": "The Sandy Hook mass school shooting in Connecticut",
        "answerC": "The victims of the Virgina Tech massacre",
        "answerD": "The Manchester mass shooting at an Ariana Grande concert"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- This San Francisco based rock band was fined $1,000 for onstage profanity in Oklahoma City back in 1970.",
        "correct": "Jefferson Airplane",
        "answerA": "Jefferson Airplane",
        "answerB": "The Steve Miller Band",
        "answerC": "The Grateful Dead",
        "answerD": "The Tubes"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Walmart refused to carry this artist's second album because of a song that condemned the chain store for selling the type of guns involved in mass shootings.",
        "correct": "Sheryl Crow",
        "answerA": "Sheryl Crow",
        "answerB": "Ariana Grande",
        "answerC": "Madonna",
        "answerD": "Ani DiFranco"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- In the summer of 2011, Punks Against Apartheid came together to convince this punk artist not to play a concert in Tel Aviv.",
        "correct": "Jello Biafra",
        "answerA": "Jello Biafra",
        "answerB": "Richard Hell",
        "answerC": "Johnny Lydon",
        "answerD": "Henry Rollins"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- What police officers association refused to join a boycott of Ice T and Time Warner in 1992 in response to the release of the song \"Cop Killer\" by the band Body Count? ",
        "correct": "The National Black Police Officers Association",
        "answerA": "The National Black Police Officers Association",
        "answerB": "National Association of Police Organizations",
        "answerC": "The All American Peace Officers Alliance",
        "answerD": "The National Peace Officers Association"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- This clarinetist and bandleader was blacklisted and brought before the House on Un-American Activities for having attended Communist meetings in 1950's.",
        "correct": "Artie Shaw",
        "answerA": "Artie Shaw",
        "answerB": "Woody Allen",
        "answerC": "Benny Goodman",
        "answerD": "Tommy Dorsey"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Walmart and K-Mart wouldn't stock the 1994 Nirvana album \"In Utero\" because of what song?",
        "correct": "\"Rape Me\"",
        "answerA": "\"Rape Me\"",
        "answerB": "\"I Hate Myself and Want to Die\"",
        "answerC": "\"Serve the Servants\"",
        "answerD": "\"Pennyroyal Tea\""
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- This rap group called for a boycott of Arizona in the early 1990's for its refusal to recognize Martin Luther King Jr's. birthday as an official holiday.",
        "correct": "Public Enemy",
        "answerA": "Public Enemy",
        "answerB": "Poor Righteous Teachers",
        "answerC": "Stetsasonic",
        "answerD": "Black Sheep"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Stevie Wonder has boycotted Florida since 2010 after Robert Zimmerman gunned down, and was acquitted of murdering, this unarmed black teen.",
        "correct": "Trayvon Martin",
        "answerA": "Trayvon Martin",
        "answerB": "Michael Brown",
        "answerC": "Breona Taylor",
        "answerD": "Stephon Clark"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- The organizers of Woodstock in 1969 decided not to invite this band due to the lead singer's recent arrest in Miami on indecent exposure.",
        "correct": "The Doors",
        "answerA": "The Doors",
        "answerB": "The Rolling Stones",
        "answerC": "The Beatles",
        "answerD": "Pink Floyd"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Sinead O'Conner was booed on stage at a Bob Dylan tribute concert a couple weeks after she did what on Saturday Night Live in 1992?",
        "correct": "Rip up a picture of the Pope",
        "answerA": "Rip up a picture of the Pope",
        "answerB": "Rip up a picture of John Major",
        "answerC": "Rip up a picture of George Bush",
        "answerD": "Rip up a picture of Dennis Miller"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- In 2010 this all Black, female singing group released the song \"Are We A Nation?\" in response to SB 1070, an anti-immigration law passed by Arizona.",
        "correct": "Sweet Honey in the Rock",
        "answerA": "Sweet Honey in the Rock",
        "answerB": "Destiny's Child",
        "answerC": "En Vogue",
        "answerD": "TLC"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Rihanna refused the NFL's offer to play the halftime super bowl show in 2019 to show solidarity with which athlete?",
        "correct": "Colin Kaepernic",
        "answerA": "Colin Kaepernic",
        "answerB": "Eric Reid",
        "answerC": "Reggie Williams",
        "answerD": "Tom Brady"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- In 1972 David Bowie came out as bisexual in an interview with what music magazine?",
        "correct": "Melody Maker",
        "answerA": "Melody Maker",
        "answerB": "Circus Magazine",
        "answerC": "Sounds",
        "answerD": "Rolling Stone"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Elvis Costello has refused to play in this country due to their treatment of residents of the Gaza Strip.",
        "correct": "Israel",
        "answerA": "Israel",
        "answerB": "Egypt",
        "answerC": "Iraq",
        "answerD": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- In 1999 the National Fraternal Order of Police called for a boycott of Rage Against the Machine and the Beastie Boys for their support of what political prisoner?",
        "correct": "Mumia Abu Jamal",
        "answerA": "Mumia Abu Jamal",
        "answerB": "Geronimo Pratt",
        "answerC": "Marilyn Buck",
        "answerD": "David Gilbert"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- Police organizations across the U.S. called for a boycott of this group for their 1988 song \"Fuck tha Police.\"",
        "correct": "NWA",
        "answerA": "NWA",
        "answerB": "Public Enemy",
        "answerC": "X- Clan",
        "answerD": "EPMD"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- In 2015 the band Wilco decided to boycott this state due to its passage of the Religious Freedom Restoration Act, a law that legalizes discrimination against LGBTQI residents.",
        "correct": "Arizona",
        "answerA": "Arizona",
        "answerB": "Maine",
        "answerC": "Texas",
        "answerD": "Iowa"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- The University of Minnesota banned this artist in 1952 for his communist political beliefs.",
        "correct": "Paul Robeson",
        "answerA": "Paul Robeson",
        "answerB": "Harry Belafonte",
        "answerC": "John Coltrane",
        "answerD": "Louis Armstrong"
    },
    {
        "question": "SHUT UP AND SING- The Miami Fraternal Order of Police called for a boycott of this artist following her Super Bowl performance in which she led dancers dressed like Black Panthers in a halftime performance of the song \"Formation.\"",
        "correct": "Beyoncé",
        "answerA": "Beyoncé",
        "answerB": "Azealia Banks",
        "answerC": "Lorde",
        "answerD": "Nicki Minaj"
    }
]